Aw.
什麼嘛
Are you already turning back?
你們要回去了嗎
Who's there?
是誰
She's emitting such an intense aura… Who is this girl?
這個散發著奇妙壓迫感的 少女是怎麼回事
Rud, this is bad!
路德 大事不妙了
Oh, dear.
搞什麼
Did I set it so that Dark Skeletons would continue to spawn?
這裡的設定 是會繼續出現黑暗骷髏嗎
Set?
設定？
If we get attacked by four of them at once…
在這邊一次遭到四隻攻擊的話…
She took all of them down in one hit.
居然一擊就打倒了
I didn't expect
沒想到
a demon lord-class guardian would appear.
居然會出現魔王等級的守護者
Demon lord-class?
魔王等級？
I thought
那個會出現黑暗骷髏的設定
I'd already disabled that.
我應該已經刪掉了啊
Is this girl the labyrinth guardian?
難道 這位少女就是迷宮守護者？
Surrender yourself to my Demon Eye!
屈服於我的魔眼吧
THE STRONGEST TANK'S LABYRINTH RAIDS
《最強肉盾的迷宮攻略～擁有稀少技能體力9999的肉盾，被勇者隊伍辭退了》
What's with this ridiculously powerful magic?
這強得離譜的魔力是怎麼回事
But I can still handle this much.
不過 這種程度我還撐得下去
You actually managed to get out of that without a status ailment.
居然有人可以在接了那一招後 還沒有陷入異常狀態
God's skill is indeed something.
"神之技能"果然不好對付
Are you the guardian of this labyrinth?
妳就是這個迷宮的守護者嗎
Correct.
沒錯
But you don't seem intimidated
不過你看到我
by me at all.
竟然一點都不感到害怕呀
After all, you look like a cute girl.
畢竟妳的外表就像個可愛的女孩啊
Cute?
我很可愛嗎
My, you have such a way with words.
這話聽著真讓人高興
Don't be fooled, Rud!
別被她騙了 路德
She's a 300-year-old granny!
這傢伙可是個超過300歲的老太婆啊
Silence, Marius!
別給我在那邊多嘴 瑪里烏斯
You are but a fallen demon lord!
你不過是個吊車尾的魔王罷了
Marius is my friend.
瑪里烏斯是我的同伴
I ask that you do not harm him.
能請妳不要傷害他嗎
I see.
原來如此
The fallen demon lord has joined the likes of human.
吊車尾魔王變成人類的同伴了啊
Not exactly.
我並非想成為人類的同伴
I simply dislike the rest of you demon lords.
只是討厭你們這些魔王罷了
I see…
這樣啊…
Regardless,
不過
do not get in my way, Demon Lord Marius.
你可別妨礙我喔 魔王瑪里烏斯
You should be aware that you are no match for me.
你應該知道自己贏不過我吧
Marius might not be able to take you down on his own,
光靠瑪里烏斯一個人 或許真的贏不過妳
but you're up against more
但是 現在站在妳面前的
than just him.
可不只瑪里烏斯一個人
And?
那又如何？
Your powers are far from those of a demon lord.
你們每個人的力量 都和我們這些魔王相差甚遠喔
It's true that alone, a human's power is nothing to fear.
一個人類所擁有的力量 確實不足為懼
We can't conquer labyrinths alone.
正因為我們無法獨自攻略迷宮
That is why we form parties.
所以才會像這樣組隊互相幫忙
To raid them together?
攻略迷宮嗎
Then let's see if you can defeat me, the guardian of the Caird Labyrinth,
那麼就讓我看看你們 在我這個凱路德迷宮的守護者
Amos Rose,
亞蒙 斯蘿絲的面前
with your so-called teamwork.
是否也能用所謂的 團隊合作來打敗我吧
Foolish humans!
愚蠢的人類唷
Such powerful magic!
好強大的魔力
We just have to take her on.
只能硬著頭皮上了
"Sacrificial Shield"!
"犧牲之盾"
"Taunt"!
"挑釁"
Such power…
好驚人的威力
How dare you hurt my sister!
竟敢傷害姊姊
She deflected it with a tornado.
居然用龍捲風把攻擊彈開了
Even with "Taunt,"
就算使用了"挑釁"
she won't focus only on me.
也不會只盯著我這裡嗎
Although it's impressive,
雖然確實挺厲害的
this level of attack won't hurt me at all.
但這點程度的攻擊根本傷不到我
Then we'll keep attacking until we do.
那我就一直攻擊到打到妳為止
I can easily evade
那種攻擊
that kind of attack with wind magic…
我用風魔法就能輕鬆躲開…
Don't think you can stay in the air forever!
別以為妳能一直飄在空中喔
That hurt…
好痛
What a nuisance…
真是個聒噪的女人
Her physical strength is no joke.
她的體能真不是蓋的
How do we break through?
該怎麼突破才好呢
Don't worry, I can keep up with her.
別擔心 我跟得上她
Is this the extent of your abilities?
你們就這點程度嗎
"Taunt"!
"挑釁"
What's the matter?
怎麼啦
You won't get me with those random attacks.
這樣胡亂攻擊 可是打不到我的喔
I'm not attacking randomly.
我可不是在胡亂攻擊
Flash magic stone!
閃光魔法石
What's that? It's blinding!
什麼東西 好刺眼
How about that?
怎麼樣啊
What is that?
那是什麼
Is this tempest the result of the magic overflow from earlier?
這股暴風是剛才那些 溢出來的魔力變化而成的嗎
It appears I was careless.
看來是我太大意了
My apologies.
抱歉囉 各位
Nin, heal everyone up.
妮恩 幫所有人回復
Got it.
知道了
I'll also cast some buffs. Gather around, everyone.
我會順便幫大家施輔助魔法 你們都靠過來一點
That girl is on an entirely different level
那傢伙
from the monsters
跟我們以前交手過的魔物
we've faced before.
完全不是同個等級的吧
Yeah.
是啊
But as long as we stand united, no monster is our match.
不過只要我們同心協力 任何魔物都不是我們的對手
I will fight hard for Master and Lady Manicia.
為了主人和瑪妮西婭大人 我會努力奮戰的
Me too.
我也是
Same here, of course.
我當然也是
After all, this is a chance to defeat a demon lord.
畢竟這可是能打倒魔王的大好機會啊
Great.
很好
We'll attack once the storm calms.
等暴風停下後 我們就上吧
A wolf?
狼？
It looks just like a Fenrir.
簡直像芬里爾一樣
Marius, can you fight in your monster form?
瑪里烏斯能用魔物型態跟她對戰嗎
If you don't mind me attacking indiscriminately.
如果你不介意我敵友不分 隨意攻擊的話
Suppose it's better for you to stay in this form then.
那你還是保持現在這樣就好了
This will reduce her chances
如此一來
of attacking the other attackers.
就能減少她去攻擊攻擊手的機會
Next, let's see how long I can hold up
接下來 就看我面對這隻大魔獸
against this giant monster.
可以撐到什麼時候了
That hardly did any damage to her.
幾乎沒什麼傷到她
Her fur is as tough as an armour.
她的毛簡直堅固得像盔甲一樣
Keep your eyes on me!
別東張西望的
Those fangs are no joke.
要是被那種獠牙咬到 可不是開玩笑的啊
But her attacks have gotten much simpler.
不過她的攻擊方式很單調
My shield force is draining fast because of the consecutive hits.
因為承受了連續攻擊 護盾快耗盡了
Prepare to cast long-distance magic.
準備施展遠距離魔法
Doesn't seem very effective.
看起來似乎沒什麼效果呢
It's a battle against the guardian.
畢竟是與守護者戰鬥
We've been prepared for this to be a long fight.
我們本來就做好了長期抗戰的覺悟
Her attacks are actually getting stronger!
攻擊居然變得更沉重了
Dang, I can't catch a break.
可惡 真想找個時機喘口氣
Sorry, Rud.
抱歉 路德
Took me some time
為了凝聚力量
to gather my strength.
我稍微花了一點時間
You're good, don't worry about it.
沒事 你做得很好
He actually cut through that fur armour.
居然能將那宛如 盔甲般堅硬的毛切斷
As expected of Marius.
不愧是瑪里烏斯
Why is she howling?
為什麼突然嘶吼
Rud, just in case,
路德 為了以防萬一
I'm casting three spells that'll nullify status ailments.
我幫你們三個施展 能讓異常狀態無效化的魔法
But I won't be able to heal you guys in the meantime, so be careful.
但那段期間我沒辦法幫忙回復傷害 你們小心一點
Got it.
我知道了
Rud, are you okay?
路德 你沒事吧
I'm fine. My shield force seems to be holding up.
沒事 護盾看起來還撐得住
As long as I don't go down,
只要我沒有倒下
with their strength, we won't lose.
以他們幾個的實力 我們是不會輸的
We have to keep pushing through.
得努力撐下去才行
I'll persist until the end.
我會就這樣堅持到最後的
"Taunt"!
"挑釁"
She's resilient.
這傢伙還真頑強
But her movements are starting to slow down.
不過她的動作開始變遲鈍了
What's going on?
怎麼回事
What's with that green gust?
那陣綠色的風到底是什麼
Whatever it is,
管它那是什麼
I'll slice it apart!
看我全部劈開
Marius!
瑪里烏斯
Judging from that attack,
看那攻擊方式
it seems to be a wind barrier that slashes anyone who comes near it.
應該是能用風 把靠近的人斬碎的防護罩吧
The magic stone on her forehead
她額頭那個石頭…
didn't shine so brightly
在展開防護罩前
before she put up the barrier.
並沒有那麼閃爍
Maybe if we destroy that stone,
或許只要破壞掉那顆石頭
we'll be able to defeat her.
就有辦法打敗她了
But
但是
we can't get close to her at all with that gust.
因為那陣風的關係 我們完全無法靠近她啊
Nin, use your magic to cancel it.
妮恩 麻煩妳用一下解除魔法
After that, we'll attack together.
然後所有人一起攻擊那裡
Got it.
我知道了
In the radiance of the holy light,
在神聖的光芒之下
the power of darkness…
黑暗之力啊
We need to buy time for Nin.
我們要努力幫妮恩爭取時間
Quietly emerging within
於白色波動中靜靜浮現
the unseen brilliance of white waves…
看不見的光彩之中
It's getting hard to breathe
因為強風不斷吹過來
because of the wind.
變得有些難以呼吸
Just that alone is hard enough,
光是這樣就夠難受了
and we've still got to deal with the wind blades.
還總是有風刃砍過來
This is hell…
簡直像地獄一樣痛苦
With the light of mercy shining into the darkness…
伴隨著照進黑暗的耀眼慈悲
-Even so, I have to hold on. -dissipate in silence.
-即便如此 我也要撐下去 -寂靜地消散吧
Prepare yourselves!
徹底做好防護
If we're attacked…
如果遭到攻擊…
She's trying to stop us from getting closer.
是不想讓我們靠近她嗎
Render it all void!
化為無力吧
Cease your pointless struggle.
不要再做無謂的掙扎了
I've removed the wind barrier.
我把風的防護罩解除了
Destroy the stone now!
趁現在把那顆石頭破壞掉
You won't escape!
不會讓妳逃跑的
She blocked all the attacks on the magic stone.
對魔石的攻擊都被擋下了嗎
But in doing so, she also left her chest vulnerable.
但胸前也因此變得毫無防備
Get her, Rud!
上吧 路德
My shield force has been depleted by almost 30,000.
我的護盾目前被消耗了將近三萬點
Take this!
接招吧
"Life Conversion"!
"生命轉換"
That's…
那是…
different from a barrier.
跟盔甲不同
That's offensive wind magic!
那是攻擊用的風魔法
Everyone, dodge!
所有人立即躲開
Oh, no!
糟糕
That's the sound of the shield breaking.
剛才那是 護盾破碎的聲音
Rud!
路德
I must hold on…
撐下去 撐下去啊
If I use up all my shield force
如果在這裡耗盡護盾
and get seriously injured,
導致重傷的話
I'll die!
只有死路一條
Rud…
路德…
Has it stopped?
停下來了嗎
Rud, are you all right?
路德 你沒事吧
Yeah, I barely made it through.
嗯 勉強撐過來了
Lilia!
姊姊
Marius!
瑪里烏斯
Hang in there!
你們振作一點啊
Rud…
路德…
Thank goodness you two are still alive.
太好了 幸好你們還活著
Luna, Nin,
露娜 妮恩
heal them.
妳們幫他們兩個回復
They'll be killed
否則她再次發動攻擊時
if she launches another attack.
他們會被殺掉的
You've used up all your shield force.
你的護盾已經耗盡了
It's too dangerous.
這樣太危險了
I can still use my skills without it.
就算沒有護盾 我還是可以使用技能
I can still fight.
我還可以繼續戰鬥
Besides, I'm the only one here who can stop her.
而且這裡只有我可以擋下她
Got it.
我知道了
Luna. Lily.
露娜 莉莉
Moreover, I'm the one who selfishly
而且任性地說想來這裡的人
dragged everyone here.
本來就是我
They came because of me.
既然他們都陪我來了
It's my responsibility to protect all of them.
我就得負起責任保護好大家
I'm feeling the pain without the shield…
因為護盾耗盡 開始感受得到疼痛了
At this rate, I'm going to be crushed!
這樣下去會被壓扁的
Wind magic?
風魔法？
No?
不用嗎
She can't use any more magic.
不 是用不出來嗎
She's weak.
她已經變得很虛弱了
We're so close…
只差一點就能打倒她了嗎
I hate to say it,
雖然很不甘心
but we'll have to retreat for now…
但今天只能先撤退…
I can still fight.
我還可以戰鬥
Nin, Luna, prepare your magic.
妮恩 露娜 請準備施展魔法
From now on,
接下來
I'll be the attacker.
我會作為攻擊手負責戰鬥
Lily, what are you saying?
莉莉 妳在說什麼啊
I'll use "Fusion" and take Lilia's place.
我會用"融合"技能 代替姊姊進行戰鬥
She's been weakened.
既然她已經這麼虛弱了
All it takes is a little more and we will defeat her.
應該再一下下就能打倒她
But…
但是
Rud,
路德
you said you'd listen to my request.
你不是說會答應我的願望嗎
I can still fight!
我真的還可以戰鬥
What a reckless one.
真是個愛亂來的傢伙呢
I understand.
我知道了
I'll block all the attacks.
我會負責擋下攻擊的
I'll help too.
我也來幫忙
Let's take her down with all we have!
用盡全力把她打倒吧
Yes!
好的
I didn't realise how much power I'd lose
沒想到失去護盾後
without my shield.
力氣會變得這麼小
But
但是
I've got to buy her time.
我得幫忙爭取時間才行
Rud!
路德
Thanks, Nin.
抱歉 妮恩
Lily, are you ready?
莉莉 妳準備好了嗎
Ready.
我準備好了
I'm not done yet.
還沒完喔
Rud!
路德
Her speed isn't too different from when Lilia's in control,
雖然速度和莉莉亞主導的 融合狀態沒什麼差別
but unlike her,
但是莉莉和莉莉亞不同
Lily's moves are too simple.
她的動作太單調
They're too predictable.
馬上就被對方摸透了
Sorry.
不好意思
I'm not used to this body yet.
我還沒辦法有效地使用這副身體
In that case,
既然如此
fight as you usually do.
就照妳平時那樣戰鬥吧
Lilia's out cold anyway.
反正莉莉亞現在也昏過去了
Don't worry about her.
妳沒必要顧慮她
Fight in your own way.
就照妳的風格去戰鬥吧
My own way?
照我的風格？
I'll do my best to buy you time until you get used to it.
在妳習慣前 我會努力幫妳爭取時間
So take your time.
所以妳就慢慢準備吧
Got it.
我知道了
Although,
雖然
given the current situation, it's a tall order,
就現在的情況來說 我們根本沒時間悠悠哉哉地準備
but my comrade is fighting so hard to change.
但是我的同伴 正為了做出改變而努力奮鬥
So, it's my job
那麼 身為她的同伴
to support her.
就應該助她一臂之力吧
Rud!
路德
Curses.
可惡
In my current state,
看來現在的我
it's really hard for me to do my job as the tank.
很難盡到肉盾的職責 幫忙爭取時間
I think I'm going to pass out from the pain…
就連現在也痛到快昏過去了
No, these are just excuses.
不 這都只是藉口罷了
No matter what happens,
不論面臨什麼狀況
it's my job to protect my party.
我都應該保護好自己的同伴
Marius used mana as his shield force.
瑪里烏斯好像都把魔力 化為護盾使用
If I do the same,
如果我也能那樣
maybe I can continue to fight.
或許就能繼續戰鬥了
Rud, she's heading towards you!
路德 她過去你那裡了
It's not perfect, but it worked.
雖然不是很完美 但還是成功了
Still, this isn't enough.
不過 光是現在這樣還不夠
I need to focus my mana
我要更努力地感受自己的魔力
and transform it into my shield force!
並將它展開化為護盾
I can move more agilely, just like when I still had my shield force.
可以像有護盾包覆在身上時 那般輕盈地活動身體了
The pain in my arm is fading too.
手臂也漸漸沒那麼痛了
So that's how you do it.
原來就是這麼做的嗎
She sped up her attacks.
她的攻擊速度變快了
Is she getting anxious?
是開始著急了嗎
Unleash more mana.
再把身上的魔力多釋放一些出來
I can move as freely as I did
現在可以跟有護盾包覆在身上時
when I had my shield force surrounding me.
一樣自在地活動了
It's time for the counterattack!
反擊時間開始了
Lily, now!
莉莉 趁現在
This is different from Lilia.
跟姊姊不同
This is my way of fighting!
這是屬於我的戰鬥方式
What power!
好強大的威力
Did she enchant the sword with all elements?
是把各種屬性的魔法附到劍上了嗎
Let's end it with this!
就用這招一決勝負吧
She's planning to strike with all four elements at once!
難道她打算一口氣 用四種屬性的魔法砍過去嗎
Lily! Are you okay?
莉莉 妳沒事吧
I'm okay…
沒事
Thank you, Rud.
謝謝你 路德
That's my line.
這是我該說的話
We won today because of you.
我們今天能贏 都是多虧了妳喔
It wasn't just me.
這不是我一個人的功勞喔
Now, take a little break.
現在妳就稍微休息一下吧
Amos,
亞蒙
do you want to continue?
妳還想繼續戰鬥嗎
I cannot even move anymore.
我早就已經動不了了好嗎
You put up an excellent fight.
你們真的很厲害呢
I never thought I'd see the day I'd be defeated.
沒想到我竟然也有被打敗的一天
I'm looking for a magic stone that can grant any wish.
我在找可以實現任何願望的魔石
Do you know anything about that?
妳有沒有什麼頭緒呢
Here, take it.
來 拿去吧
Thanks.
謝謝妳
Never expected my opponent to thank me. That is a surprise indeed.
對手居然反過來跟我道謝 這可真是出乎我的意料
Well? Are you not going to deliver the final blow?
那麼 你不給我最後一擊嗎
Or are you perhaps the type that enjoys tormenting pretty girls?
難道你是那種 以折磨美少女為樂的人嗎
You said you were a demon lord.
妳不是說自己是魔王嗎
Are there any other demon lords besides you?
除了妳以外 還有其他魔王嗎
Of course.
當然有
Though, I do not know the exact number.
但我也不知道實際上有多少人
What is their objective?
魔王們的目的是什麼？
Among demon lords, there is a popular game
魔王們之間很流行一種遊戲
of how to destroy this world.
那就是該如何破壞掉這個世界
And what is your goal?
那麼 妳的目的是什麼
Do you seek to be an enemy of the humans as a demon lord?
是想作為魔王 與人類為敵
Or do you just want to fight strong opponents?
還是單純想跟強勁的對手戰鬥呢
You have an intention.
你是有什麼話想說嗎
Yes.
沒錯
Speak away.
說說看吧
Will you help us?
妳願意幫助我們嗎
If the demon lords
如果之後
are coming after the humans,
魔王會來招惹人類
I plan to gather forces strong enough to resist them.
那我想網羅一些 足以對抗他們的戰力
Then simply put a slave bracelet on me and make me obey your command.
那就直接給我戴上奴隸手環 讓我服從你不就好了嗎
I don't like to force others against their will.
我不喜歡那樣強迫別人
That's why I'm asking for your cooperation.
所以我想拜託妳幫助我們
An amusing one you are, indeed.
你真是個有趣的傢伙呢
Well, I'm not particularly attached to my identity as a demon lord.
反正我也不是很在意魔王這個身分
Rather, since you have extended an invitation,
不如說 既然你都願意接納我了
I shall gladly become your ally.
那我當然很樂意成為你們的同伴
Thank you.
謝謝妳
Now, let's return to the city…
那麼 我們先回鎮上…
What's the matter?
怎麼了？
I am tired.
我累了啦
I can't take another step. Carry me.
已經一步都走不動了 抱我回去嘛
Eh?
咦
And thus,
就這樣
we successfully persuaded Amos Rose,
我們成功說服凱路德迷宮的守護者
the guardian of Caird Labyrinth, to join our forces.
亞蒙斯蘿絲成為我們的同伴
After that,
後來
the two major clans held another ball.
兩大戰團再次舉辦了舞會
And I…
而我…
We've successfully raided Caird Labyrinth.
我們戰團成功攻略凱路德迷宮了
Is this the map of the 51st floor?
這就是第51層的地圖？
You're kidding!
開玩笑的吧
In exchange for this map and information,
我將拿這份地圖和情報作為交換
I request an alliance with the two clans.
向兩大戰團發出同盟申請
I announced that in front of everyone.
就這樣 我在眾人面前如此宣布
Of course,
當然
I didn't reveal that the guardian had become our ally.
這次也沒對外公布 守護者成為了我們的同伴
After successfully forming an alliance with the two major clans,
成功與兩大戰團結盟後
we embarked on our journey back to Avancier.
我們準備返回阿凡錫亞
I want to see Manicia soon…
好想快點見到瑪妮西婭喔
Rud.
路德
Li…
莉…
Shh. You'll wake everyone.
這樣會吵醒大家的 請你小聲一點
Thank you for your help in the labyrinth battle.
之前在迷宮戰鬥時 真的很謝謝你
It's nothing. And I told you, didn't I?
那沒什麼 而且我不是說過了嗎
It was thanks to you…
當時是多虧有妳才…
We won because of everyone's efforts.
這次之所以能獲勝 是大家的功勞
But
但是
it was thanks to you that I could fight until the end.
我能戰鬥到最後 是路德的功勞
Thank you.
謝謝你
I'm going back to sleep.
那我回去睡覺囉
What was that about?
剛才那是怎麼回事
And she fell asleep right away.
而且她居然馬上睡著了
I'll just have to ask her later
只能之後再問她
what that kiss meant.
那個吻是什麼意思了
I should just sleep…
現在還是先睡覺吧
Rud.
路德
Lilia!
莉莉亞
Did she see that?
難道她看到剛才那一幕了？
Thank you for what you did in the labyrinth.
之前在迷宮戰鬥時 謝謝你了
I heard your voice.
你的聲音 我清楚地聽到了
That's all.
我只是想告訴你這個而已
After arriving in Avancier,
到了阿凡錫亞後
we rushed to Manicia.
我們馬上趕往瑪妮西婭身邊
Manicia, use this magic stone.
瑪妮西婭 快用這顆魔石吧
How do you feel?
怎麼樣？
I feel so much better.
感覺很好 身體也變得輕盈多了
Thank you so much,
亞蒙小姐
Miss Amos.
真的很謝謝妳
There's not much I can do for you,
雖然我能為亞蒙小姐做的事情不多
but I'll put my best effort into preparing three meals
但是每天的三餐
and afternoon tea for you.
以及下午3點的點心 我都會用心準備的
So, please enjoy yourself
所以在這裡的期間
during your stay here.
還請妳不用客氣 儘管吃吧
Being warmly welcomed by such a lovely human is a delight.
能受到妳這樣可愛的人類盛情款待 感覺還挺不賴的呢
And the snacks are delicious too.
而且點心也很好吃
I shall remain in this town for the time being.
我就暫時留在這個鎮上打發時間吧